<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>karl pribram &#8211; An Autonomous Agent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/karl-pribram/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>exploring the noosphere</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 03:49:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Opening the Doors of Perception – Anthony Peake</title>
		<link>/2018/08/opening-the-doors-of-perception-anthony-peake/</link>
				<comments>/2018/08/opening-the-doors-of-perception-anthony-peake/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 03:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anthony peake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dmt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hologram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karl pribram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roger penrose]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2548</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In Opening the Doors of Perception, Anthony Peake strings together research in epilepsy, migraines, autism, Alzheimer’s disease, schizophrenia, and entheogens in an attempt to understand human consciousness. Are we living in a simulation? What is Orchestrated Objective Reduction (Orch-OR) and what can it tell us about ourselves? How is it that flickering light can trigger an [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="https://www.anthonypeake.com/product/opening-the-doors-of-perception/">Opening the Doors of Perception</a>, Anthony Peake strings together research in epilepsy, migraines, autism, Alzheimer’s disease, schizophrenia, and entheogens in an attempt to understand human consciousness. Are we living in a simulation? What is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orchestrated_objective_reduction">Orchestrated Objective Reduction (Orch-OR)</a> and what can it tell us about ourselves? How is it that flickering light can trigger an altered state of consciousness? What is the relationship between the Eidolon and the Daemon? These are just some of the questions pondered and developed by Peake. Opening the Doors of Perception provides the reader with some fascinating research which will hopefully open ones mind to some really powerful insights.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2018/08/opening-the-doors-of-perception-anthony-peake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Holographic Universe &#8211; Michael Talbot</title>
		<link>/2016/01/the-holographic-universe-michael-talbot/</link>
				<comments>/2016/01/the-holographic-universe-michael-talbot/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 23:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david bohm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karl pribram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael talbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stanislav grof]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1391</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[After watching an interview with Michael Talbot on YouTube, I was eager to read his book, The Holographic Universe. Despite being published in 1991, the book contains a wide range of references and resources perfect for any reader in 2016 interested in the boundary between science and the paranormal. I recommend this book, not because [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After watching an <a href="https://youtu.be/6rgYz_BU2Ew" target="_blank">interview with Michael Talbot</a> on YouTube, I was eager to read his book, <a href="http://amzn.com/0062014102" target="_blank">The Holographic Universe</a>. Despite being published in 1991, the book contains a wide range of references and resources perfect for any reader in 2016 interested in the boundary between science and the paranormal. I recommend this book, not because it provides profound new insight, but because of the huge number of paranormal examples (if legitimate) and historical occurrences with which any reader may have a difficult time fitting into their framework of reality. Of course, it is unwise to accept anything you read as truth; however, the source material is listed and the reader can stroll down any path he/she wishes in their own personal investigation of these topics. My own path is now taking me into the work of Dr. Stanislav Grof,  Rick Strassman, etc&#8230; and topics such as LSD, DMT, NDEs and OBEs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2016/01/the-holographic-universe-michael-talbot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
