<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>randall carlson &#8211; An Autonomous Agent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/randall-carlson/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>exploring the noosphere</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 07:49:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.0.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Massive Crater and Younger Dryas</title>
		<link>/2019/01/massive-crater-and-younger-dryas/</link>
		<comments>/2019/01/massive-crater-and-younger-dryas/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 03:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graham hancock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[randall carlson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2584</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bright Insight did a concise summary of this news and its potential implications. Worth the watch. Staggering, can you even imagine what an object ten billion tons traveling at 12 miles per second&#8230; does to an ice sheet two miles thick. Also consider this article on meteorite strew fields in order to understand that this [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bright Insight did a concise summary of this news and its potential implications. Worth the watch. Staggering, can you even imagine what an object ten billion tons traveling at 12 miles per second&#8230; does to an ice sheet two miles thick. Also consider <a href="http://www.woreczko.pl/meteorites/features/glossary-StrewnField.htm">this article</a> on meteorite strew fields in order to understand that this event could have had multiple impact sites which could be related to the formation of the Carolina Bays.</p>
<p>The 12,000 Year old Comet that Landed on TEDTalks…and Erased Ancient Civilization &#8211; Greenland Crater</p>
<div id="hMTTFLiOwX0" class="youtube" style="width: 100%; height: 360px;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2019/01/massive-crater-and-younger-dryas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Casual Randall Carlson</title>
		<link>/2018/09/casual-randall-carlson/</link>
		<comments>/2018/09/casual-randall-carlson/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 04:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteorite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[randall carlson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2566</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Randall Carlson does a nice job explaining subjects which would otherwise be incredibly dense. I especially enjoyed this entire series: Cosmography 101. In this series he points out that ancient humans around the time of the last ice age appear to have been cosmographists. With this in mind he explores various scenarios of what might [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Randall Carlson does a nice job explaining subjects which would otherwise be incredibly dense. I especially enjoyed this entire series: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLTRcDAFHjDSg-bjFZevjMQYOZunJJ-K4k">Cosmography 101</a>. In this series he points out that ancient humans around the time of the last ice age appear to have been cosmographists. With this in mind he explores various scenarios of what might have occurred based on geological evidence. Once you finish hearing what Carlson presents I am certain you will know more than you wanted about the Younger Dryas. You will also encounter many comprehensive descriptions of comets and asteroids. Unfortunately for Carlson, his ideas on the events of the last ice age are an anathema to some of the worlds popular ideologies: those who hold a religious based on the Bible&#8217;s account of a supernatural guiding force and those who hold a scientific view based on gradualism. If you maintain a religious understanding, then the proof that these historical events occurred through purely physical interactions between material things following mathematical laws, then you will most likely close your attention to the evidence immediately. The same refusal will occur by those scientifically oriented who think their already correct view of this time era is true and scientifically valid. Dare to be challenged?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/YSIproductions/playlists?view=50&amp;sort=dd&amp;shelf_id=4">Randall Carlson YouTube Lectures</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2018/09/casual-randall-carlson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
