<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>autocosmocracy &#8211; An Autonomous Agent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/autocosmocracy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>exploring the noosphere</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 02:47:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Thoughts &#8211; Autocosmocracy</title>
		<link>/2016/05/thoughts-autocosmocracy/</link>
				<comments>/2016/05/thoughts-autocosmocracy/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 17:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[autocosmocracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[political science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1554</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Order can exist without a hierarchy, yet I constantly confront the word anarchy in contexts which assume its manipulated definition of disorder. This association degrades the ideas of political anarchists. To remedy this issue, I propose a new word: Autocosmocracy &#8211; a form of society in which the political relations between its members, without the aide of any hierarchical institution, continually [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Order can exist without a hierarchy, yet I constantly confront the word <em>anarchy</em> in contexts which assume its manipulated definition of disorder. This association degrades the ideas of political anarchists. To remedy this issue, I propose a new word:</p>
<blockquote><p>Autocosmocracy &#8211; a form of society in which the political relations between its members, without the aide of any hierarchical institution, continually gives rise to a self-organized society. A continuously existing society without a higher power structure; a system where authority lies in the absolute freedom of the individual. All members are autonomous agents.</p></blockquote>
<p>The world of the biologist is filled with organisms which are self-organized. In the natural sciences there are numerous phenomena in which order arises out of agents acting autonomously. Is not man himself a biological creature in the physical world?</p>
<p>Imagine a hypothetical situation where the form of civilization is an autocosmocracy &#8212; all individuals completely autonomous, bound by no institution. I would postulate that inevitably, after a certain number of generations, the civilization would form groups due to scarcity; and that these distinct groups will form their own government. These new groups will throw away the autocosmocratic forms and create novel political frameworks in order to achieve various goals. For instance, there is great dominating strength in having a mass of brutish men who will obey all commands unquestioningly. In other words, in an initial state of complete freedom and liberty, humans will group and band together. It can be shown mathematically that this will be the equilibrium state. Those individuals who fail to join a group will be out competed or destroyed by those who do join a group.</p>
<p>A similar situation occurs in the distributed cryptocurrency mining networks. This system, which is initially distributed with all individual miners acting autonomously, inevitably transforms into a network of groups due to competition and scarcity. So the natural question arises: how to prevent the formation of such groups in the presence of scarcity? Or is it a better question to ask how to eliminate scarcity?</p>
<p>In terms of Plato&#8217;s cave of shadows, it would be a society in which all members are able to discover the source of the shadows. All members would exist as philosopher kings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2016/05/thoughts-autocosmocracy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
