<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>karl marx &#8211; An Autonomous Agent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/karl-marx/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>exploring the noosphere</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 02:50:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Brief Overview of My Experiences with Stocks</title>
		<link>/2014/03/brief-overview-of-my-experiences-with-stocks/</link>
				<comments>/2014/03/brief-overview-of-my-experiences-with-stocks/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 01:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[benjamin graham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harold simmons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karl marx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stocks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warren buffett]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=83</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[My first foray into the stock market was after reading the books of the popular writer, Jim Cramer. And it resulted in buying several penny stocks which were developing &#8220;revolutionary&#8221; new products. They did rather poorly and I decided to try buying stocks of more well-known companies, like Goldman Sachs and some others which I [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">My first foray into the stock market was after reading the books of the popular writer, Jim Cramer. And it resulted in buying several penny stocks which were developing &#8220;revolutionary&#8221; new products. They did rather poorly and I decided to try buying stocks of more well-known companies, like Goldman Sachs and some others which I do not remember. This was in 2007-8 and the tiny gains from my small investments were financially negligible; however, it was an experience.</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">My knowledge of markets began to change as 2008 progressed into 2009 and I gained experience trading stocks. I lost interest in Cramer and found the work of Benjamin Graham to be far more fascinating. While in high-school I was fascinated by Benjamin Graham&#8217;s record of success and his value investing approach to choosing investments. My interest continued as an undergrad in college; I remember reading all of Graham&#8217;s articles while sitting through accounting class. Reading <i>Security Analysis </i>more than twice, I attempted to put my newly learned skills to the test. The potential to find muddied gems hidden from view by the dirty coating applied by &#8220;Mr. Market&#8221; spurred my desire to master the art.</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">There were a few stocks which I had bought at various times during the period of 2008-9; they fell and rose with the rest of the market during the roller coaster ride from which many people still feel dizzy. One was Reddy Ice, which ended up bankrupt. However, I did not have much money to invest until after the downturn. In this favorable condition I began to search through hundreds, if not thousands of stocks. The final list of suitable candidates fitting Graham&#8217;s criteria included a steel producer called Keystone Consolidated Industries. Owned mostly by Harold Simmons&#8217; Contran, the stock had a market value of $36 million. Having a pension fund the size of Texas and a decent sized steel operation (around $500 million of sales per year), I felt this was the best choice. It turned out to be a wise investment, as I finally liquidated my position when Contran finally purchased all the shares at around $9.00. Even at this price, the company&#8217;s market value was only around $100 million &#8212; a real bargain for Contran, since the pension fund had around $700 million in assets at the time and only $350 in NPV of pension obligations; not to mention the profitable steel company. Carl Icahn, the only other large shareholder, said not a word at the paltry price of $9. To this day, I still believe a fair price should have been at least $20 per share. Despite most of the value being reaped by Contran and Simmons on this transaction, I did benefit.</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">After this success (and the passing of three years), I found that I lacked the same fascination with Graham as I did a few years before. I think my interest waned as I witnessed &#8220;Mr. Market&#8221; in action and I realized first hand that market sentiment played a huge role in price determination. &#8220;How could people not see the value?&#8221; I always asked myself. &#8220;Was this a flaw in Graham&#8217;s strategy?&#8221; And it was precisely this question which led me to realize that people and markets are far from efficient. Graham&#8217;s method is only successful for a large diversified portfolio of undervalued stocks. In fact, I really think that value does not exist as an absolute quantifiable truth; value only exists as a social relationship between commodities as Marx writes in <i>Das Kapital</i>. And by doing so, its expression is subject to the whims of human emotion. It is with this perspective which I began reading about the behavior of traders and markets.</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">Today I am surprised to learn that <a href="//www.dallasnews.com/news/headlines/20131229-flashback-the-inside-story-of-harold-c.-simmons-from-huck-finn-looks-to-high-rolling-investments.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Harold Simmons passed away in December of 2013</a>. He was a clever man who grew a few thousand dollars into billions.</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2014/03/brief-overview-of-my-experiences-with-stocks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Das Kapital &#8211; Karl Marx</title>
		<link>/2014/02/das-kapital-karl-marx/</link>
				<comments>/2014/02/das-kapital-karl-marx/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capitalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[das kapital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david harvey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[didier sornette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friedrich engels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karl marx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robert prechter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=106</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Das Kapital &#8211; The three volume set by Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels may contain the theoretical underpinnings for the observations of R. N. Elliott. The fundamental interactions involved in economics via social relationships between commodities lead to the development of Elliott Waves &#8212; later expanded upon by Prechter, Sornette, and others. More on this [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/97838682010481.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/97838682010481.jpg" height="320" width="219" /></a></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"><a href="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Das_Kapital" target="_blank">Das Kapital</a> &#8211; The three volume set by Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels may contain the theoretical underpinnings for the observations of R. N. Elliott. The fundamental interactions involved in economics via social relationships between commodities lead to the development of Elliott Waves &#8212; later expanded upon by Prechter, Sornette, and others. More on this possible connection in a future post. Regardless, based on what I have read so far, I think this will be an interesting intellectual read. The well-worn hardback copy version I am reading, from a Boston library, was published in 1902; I wonder who has read this copy in the past 112 years?</div>
<p>Volume 1 &#8211; Capital: Critique of Political Economy<br />Volume 2 &#8211; Capital: The Process of Circulation of Capital<br />Volume 3 &#8211; Capital: The Process of Capitalist Production as a Whole</p>
<p>Ebook and PDF versions: <a href="https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1867-c1/" target="_blank">here</a> and <a href="https://archive.org/details/KarlMarxDasKapitalpdf" target="_blank">here</a></p>
<p>Also, for some lectures and commentary on the book see <a href="//davidharvey.org/" target="_blank">David Harvey&#8217;s website</a>.</p>
<p>Possible conception for The Organism which Marx refers to:</p>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/theorganism_small1.jpeg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/theorganism_small1.jpeg" height="240" width="400" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2014/02/das-kapital-karl-marx/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
