<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>civilization &#8211; An Autonomous Agent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/civilization/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>exploring the noosphere</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 04:07:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.9</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Casual Randall Carlson</title>
		<link>/2018/09/casual-randall-carlson/</link>
		<comments>/2018/09/casual-randall-carlson/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 04:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteorite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[randall carlson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2566</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Randall Carlson does a nice job explaining subjects which would otherwise be incredibly dense. I especially enjoyed this entire series: Cosmography 101. In this series he points out that ancient humans around the time of the last ice age appear to have been cosmographists. With this in mind he explores various scenarios of what might [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Randall Carlson does a nice job explaining subjects which would otherwise be incredibly dense. I especially enjoyed this entire series: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLTRcDAFHjDSg-bjFZevjMQYOZunJJ-K4k">Cosmography 101</a>. In this series he points out that ancient humans around the time of the last ice age appear to have been cosmographists. With this in mind he explores various scenarios of what might have occurred based on geological evidence. Once you finish hearing what Carlson presents I am certain you will know more than you wanted about the Younger Dryas. You will also encounter many comprehensive descriptions of comets and asteroids. Unfortunately for Carlson, his ideas on the events of the last ice age are an anathema to some of the worlds popular ideologies: those who hold a religious based on the Bible&#8217;s account of a supernatural guiding force and those who hold a scientific view based on gradualism. If you maintain a religious understanding, then the proof that these historical events occurred through purely physical interactions between material things following mathematical laws, then you will most likely close your attention to the evidence immediately. The same refusal will occur by those scientifically oriented who think their already correct view of this time era is true and scientifically valid. Dare to be challenged?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/YSIproductions/playlists?view=50&amp;sort=dd&amp;shelf_id=4">Randall Carlson YouTube Lectures</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2018/09/casual-randall-carlson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scale – Geoffrey West</title>
		<link>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/</link>
		<comments>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 03:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[complexity theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[didier sornette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragon-king]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geoffrey west]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa fe institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociobiology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[socionomics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2552</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Scale, by Geoffrey West, is a thought provoking book about coarse grained quantitative network theories which concern the entire human species and its interaction with the environment. Although verbose — as I think the intended audience is upper high school and entry-level college — it is clear in its depictions and explanations. This book is [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://a.co/0tTatb5">Scale</a>, by Geoffrey West, is a thought provoking book about coarse grained quantitative network theories which concern the entire human species and its interaction with the environment. Although verbose — as I think the intended audience is upper high school and entry-level college — it is clear in its depictions and explanations. This book is an important summary of really profound work and research performed at the Santa Fe Institute. And it is a great introduction to understanding power laws and scaling in biology and network topologies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tragedy and Hope &#8211; Carroll Quigley</title>
		<link>/2016/10/tragedy-and-hope-carroll-quigley/</link>
		<comments>/2016/10/tragedy-and-hope-carroll-quigley/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 19:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[american]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carroll quigley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[empire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1601</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tragedy and Hope by Carroll Quigley narrates and analyzes world history from the late 1800&#8217;s to 1964. Throughout Quigley&#8217;s narration he mentions details of individual people who welded enormous power and influence over events; it would be naive to suggest that they were &#8220;all powerful&#8221; &#8211; some of the time they successfully shaped history while [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><a href="https://amzn.com/094500110X">Tragedy and Hope</a></em> by Carroll Quigley narrates and analyzes world history from the late 1800&#8217;s to 1964. Throughout Quigley&#8217;s narration he mentions details of individual people who welded enormous power and influence over events; it would be naive to suggest that they were &#8220;all powerful&#8221; &#8211; some of the time they successfully shaped history while at other times they failed. It is simply the nature of the hierarchical system of organization of society which encourages and allows such influence.</p>
<p>I would agree with <a href="https://anautonomousagent.com/2016/07/the-quigley-formula-g-edward-griffin-lecture/">G. Edward Griffin</a> that conspiracy is an important force in the formation of history and is critical to understanding <em>why </em>events progress in various ways. However, we must be careful with attributing full power of determination to such forces. We should qualify with Bismarck&#8217;s comment that: &#8220;The statesman&#8217;s task is to hear God&#8217;s footsteps marching through history, and to try and catch on to His coattails as He marches past.&#8221;</p>
<p>It is humorous that most people on the far right recommend Quigley when he mentions several times in the book that he despises them and their motives. For instance on page 1244:</p>
<blockquote><p>The second most numerous group in the United States is the petty bourgeoisie, including millions of persons who regard themselves as middle class and are under all the middle-class anxieties and pressures, but often earn less money than unionized laborers. As a results of these things, they are often very insecure, envious, filled with hatreds, and are generally the chief recruits for any Radical Right, Fascist, or hate campaigns against any group that is different or which refuses to conform to middle-class values. &#8230; They form the major portion of the Republican Party&#8217;s supporters in the towns of America, as they did for the Nazis in Germany&#8230;</p></blockquote>
<p>This attitude is reflected in various forms throughout the book. On the other hand, Quigley greatly supports conservatism of an interesting type; on page 1232 he says:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8230; we might say that the whole recent controversy between conservatism and liberalism is utterly wrongheaded and ignorant. Since the true role of conservatism must be to conserve the tradition of our society, and since that tradition is a liberal tradition, the two should be closely allied in their aim at common goals.</p></blockquote>
<p>He reflects on the underlying power relationships and how they function when he continues: &#8220;So long as liberals and conservatives have as their primary goals to defend interests and to belabor each other for partisan reasons, they cannot do this.&#8221; The traditions of society cannot be conserved because the power held by special interests opposes unification.</p>
<p>Far right people are the first to tell you about grand conspiracies like the Trilateral Commission or the Round Table groups as mentioned by Quigley. In fact, it was from a clip of Alex Jones that I learned about Quigley&#8217;s book. In my own experience both the far right and far left maintain ridiculous and unrealistic outlooks and understandings of power.</p>
<p>The Western Tradition, which Quigley mentions extensively, exists in his mind, if not in the real world, as a basis for all the progress and success of the people who self-identify as &#8220;Western.&#8221; He states on page 1229 that Western Traditions consist of six core fundamental ideologies:</p>
<ol>
<li>There is a truth, a reality.</li>
<li>No person, group, or organization has the whole picture of the truth.</li>
<li>Every person of goodwill has some aspect of the truth, some vision of it from the angle of his own experience.</li>
<li>Through discussion, the aspects of the truth held by many can be pooled and arranged to form a consensus closer to the truth than any of the sources that contributed to it.</li>
<li>This consensus is a temporary approximation of the truth, which is no sooner made than new experiences and additional information make it possible for it to be reformulated in a <em>closer</em> approximation of the truth by continued discussion.</li>
<li>Thus Western man&#8217;s picture of the truth advances, by successive approximations, closer and closer to the whole truth without ever reaching it.</li>
</ol>
<p>However, Quigley is no idealist, and his thoughts help to provide a realistic understanding of the nature of power in the hierarchies which control and function on various levels in nation-states. And he does this through a narration and analysis of &#8220;history in our time.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/10/tragedy-and-hope-carroll-quigley/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Myth of the &#8220;Clash of Civilizations&#8221; &#8211; Edward Said</title>
		<link>/2016/07/the-myth-of-the-clash-of-civilizations-edward-said/</link>
		<comments>/2016/07/the-myth-of-the-clash-of-civilizations-edward-said/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 15:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edward said]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1584</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[But the work of Man is only just beginning, and it remains to conquer all the violence entrenched in the recesses of our passion&#8230; and no race possesses the monopoly of beauty, of intelligence, of force. And there is a place for all at the rendezvous of victory. &#8212; Aime Cesaire]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>But the work of Man is only just beginning, and it remains to conquer all the violence entrenched in the recesses of our passion&#8230; and no race possesses the monopoly of beauty, of intelligence, of force. And there is a place for all at the rendezvous of victory.</p>
<p>&#8212; Aime Cesaire</p></blockquote>
<div class="youtube"
     id="aPS-pONiEG8"
     style="width: 100%; height: 360px;">
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/07/the-myth-of-the-clash-of-civilizations-edward-said/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Auroville &#8211; City of the Dawn</title>
		<link>/2016/03/auroville-city-of-the-dawn/</link>
		<comments>/2016/03/auroville-city-of-the-dawn/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[auroville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sri aurobindo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venus project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1488</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[These videos provide a fascinating look at the history and ongoing development of Auroville (City of the Dawn). Founded by Mirra Alfassa as a project of the Sri Aurobindo Society, it provides an example of a community designed to inspire unity and lead the way forward for humanity. City of the Dawn is a summary of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These videos provide a fascinating look at the history and ongoing development of <a href="http://www.auroville.org/" target="_blank">Auroville</a> (City of the Dawn). Founded by Mirra Alfassa as a project of the Sri Aurobindo Society, it provides an example of a community designed to inspire unity and lead the way forward for humanity.</p>
<p>City of the Dawn is a summary of the city&#8217;s foundation and history since the late 1960&#8217;s and early 1970&#8217;s:</p>
<div class="youtube"
     id="hU40Ba4GXjE"
     style="width: 100%; height: 360px;">
</div>
<p>Auroville Towards a Sustainable Future shows the incredible ecological work required to repair and grow the land needed to sustain the city:</p>
<div class="youtube"
     id="mCCFPooVfV0"
     style="width: 100%; height: 360px;">
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/auroville-city-of-the-dawn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Magicians of the Gods &#8211; Graham Hancock</title>
		<link>/2015/11/magicians-of-the-gods-graham-hancock/</link>
		<comments>/2015/11/magicians-of-the-gods-graham-hancock/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 02:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[ancient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graham hancock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1384</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Magicians of the Gods, Graham Hancock presents the hypothesis that a civilization existed and prospered sometime either before or during the Younger Dryas. Whoever these people were, their society was wiped out due to the cataclysm of The Flood. The same flood mentioned by almost every historical culture on every continent. This comet struck the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="http://amzn.com/1250045924" target="_blank">Magicians of the Gods</a>, Graham Hancock presents the hypothesis that a civilization existed and prospered sometime either before or during the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Younger_Dryas" target="_blank">Younger Dryas</a>. Whoever these people were, their society was wiped out due to the cataclysm of The Flood. The same flood mentioned by almost every historical culture on every continent. This comet struck the polar ice cap in the northern hemisphere; the resulting impact vaporized an enormous amount of water, leading to flooding and climate disruption. It was either this initial impact or perhaps related events which caused massive worldwide displacement in the ocean&#8217;s sea levels. The reason we have little archaeological evidence, as Hancock suggests, is due to the rise in sea level which totally submerged all structures. Additionally, there have been few thorough searches in likely locations due to the disbelief of modern institutions. Hancock proposes that a likely location would be the Indonesian subcontinent, which around the Younger Dryas time was vastly larger and contained numerous river basins and plains.</p>
<p>It is fascinating to learn that the debris stream of this comet could be the source of the <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1003.0744" target="_blank">Taurid meteor stream</a>. There is even evidence that a bigger chunk of the comet lurks in this Earth crossing debris field.</p>
<p>The entire book is littered with footnotes and source references. Hancock did a lot of research and it shows. Like all human theories, I am sure some parts of it will be dis-proven while other parts shown to be entirely correct. As researchers continue to investigate underwater ruins and the mysterious underwater past of Indonesia becomes unraveled, we may indeed find evidence which requires a total renewal of our understanding of human history.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/11/magicians-of-the-gods-graham-hancock/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Profit Over People: Neoliberalism &#038; Global Order &#8211; Noam Chomsky</title>
		<link>/2014/09/profit-over-people-neoliberalism-global-order-noam-chomsky/</link>
		<comments>/2014/09/profit-over-people-neoliberalism-global-order-noam-chomsky/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 21:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[american]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capitalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noam chomsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[political science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social behavior]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=22</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In&#160;Profit Over People: Neoliberalism &#38; Global Order,&#160;Noam Chomsky critiques the economic vogue held by a large number of economists and government officials during the last quarter of the 20th century and continuing to this day. In truth, it seems as if many of our climate and social problems stem from the concerns raised by Chomsky. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">In&nbsp;<a href="//amzn.com/1888363827" target="_blank">Profit Over People: Neoliberalism &amp; Global Order</a>,&nbsp;Noam Chomsky critiques the economic vogue held by a large number of economists and government officials during the last quarter of the 20th century and continuing to this day. In truth, it seems as if many of our climate and social problems stem from the concerns raised by Chomsky. If we as a species wish to continue living in a global community on Earth &#8212; enjoying the benefits of mutual aid and global economic prosperity to achieve a greater civilization, it seems that it is necessary to address the issues presented by Chomsky. Of course, working towards such an ideal society and generating such sublime goals is always optional. The foundation upon which rests all great civilizations is the confidence and power of its people to see and seize their own destiny. Read the book and you may begin to see the light at the end of the tunnel.</div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/tumblr_lf301dKlGs1qcz0hxo1_40011.gif" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/tumblr_lf301dKlGs1qcz0hxo1_40011.gif" height="320" width="231" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/09/profit-over-people-neoliberalism-global-order-noam-chomsky/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Way of Zen &#8211; Alan Watts</title>
		<link>/2013/01/the-way-of-zen-alan-watts/</link>
		<comments>/2013/01/the-way-of-zen-alan-watts/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[alan watts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddhism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eastern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=375</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Way of Zen,&#160;by Alan Watts, introduces the western mind to the ideas of Zen. The book does a great job, almost as good as any Zen master. Highly recommended for anyone interested in Zen and its history.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/way-of-zen1.jpg" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/way-of-zen1.jpg" height="320" width="214" /></a></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"><a href="//amzn.com/0375705104" style="font-style: italic;">The Way of Zen</a>,&nbsp;by <a href="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Watts" target="_blank">Alan Watts</a>, introduces the western mind to the ideas of <a href="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zen" target="_blank">Zen</a>. The book does a great job, almost as good as any Zen master. Highly recommended for anyone interested in Zen and its history.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/01/the-way-of-zen-alan-watts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Earth at Night</title>
		<link>/2013/01/earth-at-night/</link>
		<comments>/2013/01/earth-at-night/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 21:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nasa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=384</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[All the light from human activity creates a spectacular view from space. Check out these videos: Earth from Space Video 1 Earth from Space Video 2 Earth from Space Video 3]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All the light from human activity creates a spectacular view from space. Check out these videos:</p>
<div></div>
<div><a href="//youtu.be/ev9oPUNaqXE" target="_blank">Earth from Space Video 1</a></div>
<div><a href="//youtu.be/FG0fTKAqZ5g" target="_blank">Earth from Space Video 2</a></div>
<div><a href="//youtu.be/i0_aCvuMsng" target="_blank">Earth from Space Video 3</a></div>
<div></div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/earthlights2_dmsp_big.jpg" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="200" src="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/earthlights2_dmsp_big.jpg" width="400" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/01/earth-at-night/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
