<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>physics &#8211; An Autonomous Agent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/physics/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>exploring the noosphere</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 04:07:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.9</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Scale – Geoffrey West</title>
		<link>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/</link>
		<comments>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 03:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[complexity theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[didier sornette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragon-king]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geoffrey west]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa fe institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociobiology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[socionomics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2552</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Scale, by Geoffrey West, is a thought provoking book about coarse grained quantitative network theories which concern the entire human species and its interaction with the environment. Although verbose — as I think the intended audience is upper high school and entry-level college — it is clear in its depictions and explanations. This book is [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://a.co/0tTatb5">Scale</a>, by Geoffrey West, is a thought provoking book about coarse grained quantitative network theories which concern the entire human species and its interaction with the environment. Although verbose — as I think the intended audience is upper high school and entry-level college — it is clear in its depictions and explanations. This book is an important summary of really profound work and research performed at the Santa Fe Institute. And it is a great introduction to understanding power laws and scaling in biology and network topologies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Order Out of Chaos &#8211; Ilya Prigogine and Isabelle Stengers</title>
		<link>/2018/01/order-out-of-chaos-ilya-prigogine-and-isabelle-stengers/</link>
		<comments>/2018/01/order-out-of-chaos-ilya-prigogine-and-isabelle-stengers/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 18:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[complexity theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ilya prigogine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isabelle stengers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symmetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2536</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A little bit of quantum physics, chemistry, biology and philosophy all rolled up into one important book. Order Out of Chaos (La Nouvelle Alliance as originally published in French) by Ilya Prigogine and Isabelle Stengers is a paradigm changing book. The first parts of the book are an excellent overview on the historical development of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A little bit of quantum physics, chemistry, biology and philosophy all rolled up into one important book. <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/783285.Order_Out_of_Chaos"><em>Order Out of Chaos</em></a> (<em>La Nouvelle Alliance</em> as originally published in French) by Ilya Prigogine and Isabelle Stengers is a paradigm changing book. The first parts of the book are an excellent overview on the historical development of science &#8211; the evolution of dynamics and the discovery of thermodynamics and their relationship is particularly fascinating.</p>
<p>Once the reader gets to the later parts, it becomes somewhat abstract and the reader may not be able to get through it without a background in chemistry and physics. Chapter Nine, when the phrase &#8220;Order Out of Chaos&#8221; is developed, is difficult. Despite this, it is much more accessible than a scientific paper on the subject. It may take two or three reads to fully absorb the ideas presented. Overall it is one of my favorite reads.</p>
<p>Some important conclusions from the book:</p>
<ul>
<li>The arrow of time objectively exists and it arises from non-equilibrium and irreversibility at the microscopic level.</li>
<li>The 2nd Law of Thermodynamics can be understood as a selection principal. It operates as a negative on allowable initial conditions, in other words it restricts systems with certain initial conditions from existing.</li>
<li>Time travel to the past is not allowed by thermodynamics because time reversal requires infinite information concerning the initial conditions of the system, an impossibility to an observer in the universe. This implies that information is closely connected to irreversibility and time.</li>
<li>Thermodynamics can be expressed from dynamics through the idea of correlations and internal-time operators. Thus, dynamics has been extended once again (general relativity, quantum mechanics, and chaos theory).</li>
<li>The universe as a whole is in a non-equilibrium state and it is an irreversible process with pockets of reversible dynamics.</li>
<li>In general, one of the goals of the authors is to make dynamics and thermodynamics consistent with each other.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2018/01/order-out-of-chaos-ilya-prigogine-and-isabelle-stengers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Dancing Wu Li Masters &#8211; Gary Zukav</title>
		<link>/2017/12/dancing-wu-li-masters-zukav/</link>
		<comments>/2017/12/dancing-wu-li-masters-zukav/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 05:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biocentrism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddhism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eastern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[einstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gary zukav]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard feynman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2521</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gary Zukav&#8217;s book, The Dancing Wu Li Masters, simply describes (without math) quantum physics and relativity since their inception at the beginning of the 20th century. Zukav skillfully presents the paradoxes and questions posed and asked by some of the smartest people in history including Einstein, Bohr, Born, Heisenberg, von Neumann, Feynman, etc&#8230; He carefully [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gary Zukav&#8217;s book, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Dancing_Wu_Li_Masters">The Dancing Wu Li Masters</a>, <em>simply</em> describes (without math) quantum physics and relativity since their inception at the beginning of the 20th century. Zukav skillfully presents the paradoxes and questions posed and asked by some of the smartest people in history including Einstein, Bohr, Born, Heisenberg, von Neumann, Feynman, etc&#8230; He carefully elucidates the evolution of the answers to these paradoxes and questions.</p>
<p>There are numerous analogies with eastern cosmologies which may help readers understand the wild results and conclusions of modern physics. The book is perfect for those without a strong background in the quantitative sciences who wish to understand what quantum physics reveals about the universe. Although dated, (1979) it is inspirational and should get readers excited about reading more up to date books.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2017/12/dancing-wu-li-masters-zukav/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inner Worlds, Outer Worlds (2012)</title>
		<link>/2016/05/inner-worlds-outer-worlds-2012/</link>
		<comments>/2016/05/inner-worlds-outer-worlds-2012/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 14:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cymatic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samadhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terence mckenna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1552</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Compilation of various ideas on mysticism and science.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Compilation of various ideas on mysticism and science.</p>
<p><iframe width="629" height="354" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLD8E5F0D70B62BEFE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/05/inner-worlds-outer-worlds-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wholeness and the Implicate Order &#8211; David Bohm</title>
		<link>/2015/09/wholeness-and-the-implicate-order-david-bohm/</link>
		<comments>/2015/09/wholeness-and-the-implicate-order-david-bohm/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 03:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david bohm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1334</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The collection of papers composing the book, Wholeness and the Implicate Order by David Bohm, provides an introduction to the idea of holomovement and the implicate order of the universe. In other words, the entire known and un-known universe exists as a single inseparable flow. All parts are contained in any specified part, just as [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The collection of papers composing the book, <a href="http://amzn.com/0415289793" target="_blank">Wholeness and the Implicate Order</a> by David Bohm, provides an introduction to the idea of holomovement and the implicate order of the universe. In other words, the entire known and un-known universe exists as a single inseparable flow. All parts are contained in any specified part, just as in a hologram. And all that humans observe with their biological and technological sensory apparatus are sub-regions of explicate order which form from within this whole.</p>
<p>As a metaphor, Bohm takes the experiment introduced by John Heller, shown below, and explains that the original oval shape drops of dye can be thought of as an explicate ordering of color and structure in time and space. After the experiment proceeds, this explicate order mixes into the glycerin system. Now, imagine the implicate order as consisting of the glycerin and dye system modified via the rotation. The system contains the original explicate ordering of the drops, in other words the existence of the dye as drops of individual colors is encoded by the glycerin system.</p>
<p>BUT, up to now the metaphor has been like a &#8220;time-reversal.&#8221; The real point of Bohm is that if the system is now rotated in the opposite direction, the dye will condense out of the system as an explicate order of color and shape identical to the original. This is how he suggests that the universe, i.e. the implicate order of the holomovement forms all explicate orders, including consciousness, observed by humans.</p>
<p><iframe width="629" height="472" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UpJ-kGII074?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/wholeness-and-the-implicate-order-david-bohm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nice Interview with David Bohm</title>
		<link>/2015/08/nice-interview-with-david-bohm/</link>
		<comments>/2015/08/nice-interview-with-david-bohm/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 22:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[albert einstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david bohm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1263</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[About to start reading Bohm&#8217;s Wholeness and the Implicate Order. His ideas are appealing to my own experiences and I hope to learn a great deal from his book. Pretty good interview with David Bohm:]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About to start reading Bohm&#8217;s Wholeness and the Implicate Order. His ideas are appealing to my own experiences and I hope to learn a great deal from his book. Pretty good interview with David Bohm:</p>
<div class="youtube"
     id="QI66ZglzcO0"
     style="width: 100%; height: 360px;">
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/08/nice-interview-with-david-bohm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Theories of J. Marvin Herdon</title>
		<link>/2015/06/the-theories-of-j-marvin-herdon/</link>
		<comments>/2015/06/the-theories-of-j-marvin-herdon/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 12:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvin herndon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1134</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was curious to learn about the Whole-Earth Decompression Dynamics (WEDD) theory developed by J. Marvin Herndon after I discovered that Lynn Margulis had edited and recommended his work several years ago.  After purchasing Herndon&#8217;s Earth and the Dark Side of Science and reading the foreword by Dorion Sagan, whom I respect as an excellent [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was curious to learn about the Whole-Earth Decompression Dynamics (WEDD) theory developed by J. Marvin Herndon after I discovered that Lynn Margulis had edited and recommended his work several years ago.  After purchasing <a href="http://amzn.com/1503041271" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Herndon&#8217;s Earth and the Dark Side of Science</a> and reading the foreword by Dorion Sagan, whom I respect as an excellent science writer, I began to see Herndon as a scientist who is attempting to shake the foundations of more than three distinct subject areas &#8211; Geoscience, Planetary Sciences, and Nuclear Science. Whether or not you personally think his WEDD theory is right or wrong is irrelevant to the truth. If someone thinks his theory is incorrect, then they can refute the theory with substantive evidence by publishing a paper which details the inconsistencies in logic or facts. But remember, as Feyerabend and Kuhn note repeatedly, facts are always theory laden.</p>
<p>Science is not a religion; scientists are not priests who defend a fixed doctrine. Scientists who simply ridicule or resort to name calling are doing a disservice to science in a time when science is being attacked on many fronts &#8211; by religions, governments, and corporations. Scientists who forsake truth for tenure, personal prestige or their own beliefs are just as dangerous to science as any external threat. And this does not exclude Herndon himself.</p>
<p>As a reader of science subjects, I find the ideas of Herndon to be a fresh and fascinating departure from the status-quo. This is what science is all about, proposing preposterous ideas and then proving them right or wrong. His theory is nothing short of a revolution in the subjects previously mentioned. Even if it turns out to be false, they still provide food for thought and may even perhaps result in a more developed and better understanding of the true nature of natural phenomenon.</p>
<p>In light of all the exoplanet discoveries of the Kepler Space Telescope there is even more reason to seriously consider investigating the theories presented by Herdon. Of the thousands of exoplanets discovered thus far, there is a large fraction of Jupiter type planets which lie within the orbit of Earth. In fact there are so many such exoplanets that the question should not be: &#8220;Why are there so many Jupiter type planets in such close proximity to their host star?&#8221; but should rather be: &#8220;Why does our Solar System <em>not</em> contain Jupiter type planets within Earth&#8217;s orbit?&#8221;</p>
<p>Even <em>if</em> Herdon&#8217;s theory is <em>incorrect</em> regarding the history of <em>our</em> Solar System, his proposed theory is a physical possibility, i.e. there is at least one planet or moon which has had its atmosphere stripped away in the universe. It would therefore be silly not to study the theory. Don&#8217;t mathematicians study topics which have no current application? What is the issue with studying situations that did not occur in our Solar System?</p>
<p>I suggest first reading: <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1308.5934" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">A New Basis of Geoscience: Whole-Earth Decompression Dynamics</a></p>
<p>and then reading his book mentioned earlier (his book also contains this paper, among others).</p>
<p>For a list of his papers &#8211; <a href="http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Herndon_J/0/1/0/all/0/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">J. Marvin Herdon on arXiv.org</a>.</p>
<p><iframe width="629" height="354" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SdQWipgf4B4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/06/the-theories-of-j-marvin-herdon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thorium &#8211; Kirk Sorenson</title>
		<link>/2015/05/thorium-kirk-sorenson/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/thorium-kirk-sorenson/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 01:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[documentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james mahaffey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kirk sorenson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nasa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuclear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1107</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Kirk Sorenson does an excellent job describing the current state of the American nuclear energy program and its future. He sees hope from the current enthusiasm of the Chinese, who are developing extensive nuclear reactor technology. Perhaps their focus will encourage the rest of the world. The nuclear energy field has been plagued by misconceptions [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kirk Sorenson does an excellent job describing the current state of the American nuclear energy program and its future. He sees hope from the current enthusiasm of the Chinese, who are developing extensive nuclear reactor technology. Perhaps their focus will encourage the rest of the world. The nuclear energy field has been plagued by misconceptions for decades. There is a definite need for someone to stand up and cut through all the ignorance surrounding this important subject.</p>
<p>There are probably hundreds of new reactor designs. Kirk&#8217;s favourite is the Liquid Fluoride Thorium Reactor (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liquid_fluoride_thorium_reactor" target="_blank">LFTR</a>). He talks extensively about its benefits, its problems, its safety, and how it can be put into operation. Hopefully, people will see his arguments as valid and convincing. Read more on his blog: <a href="http://energyfromthorium.com/" target="_blank">Energy from Thorium</a>. <a href="http://gordonmcdowell.com/thorium/" target="_blank">Gordon McDowell&#8217;s videos</a> present the ideas of Sorenson in a clear and concise manner and there are numerous lectures and talks given by Sorenson on YouTube.</p>
<p>I would also recommend <a href="https://anautonomousagent.com/2013/11/atomic-awakening-a-new-look-at-the-history-and-future-of-nuclear-power-james-mahaffey/" target="_blank">James Mahaffey&#8217;s book, Atomic Awakening</a>.</p>
<div class="youtube"
     id="P9M__yYbsZ4"
     style="width: 100%; height: 360px;">
</div>
<div class="youtube"
     id="Z3pxPP3m0k0"
     style="width: 100%; height: 360px;">
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/thorium-kirk-sorenson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The End of Certainty &#8211; Ilya Prigogine</title>
		<link>/2015/01/the-end-of-certainty-ilya-prigogine/</link>
		<comments>/2015/01/the-end-of-certainty-ilya-prigogine/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 20:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ilya prigogine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[math]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa fe institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stuart Kauffman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symmetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=7</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The End of Certainty by Ilya Prigogine provides insight into the natural processes which give rise to the novelty of life. Despite being published in 1997, there are so many great quotes and concepts which are still applicable today, that I will just say, &#8220;Read the book!&#8221; It will also help to read Stuart Kauffman&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="//amzn.com/0684837056" target="_blank">The End of Certainty</a> by <a href="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ilya_Prigogine" target="_blank">Ilya Prigogine</a> provides insight into the natural processes which give rise to the novelty of life. Despite being published in 1997, there are so many great quotes and concepts which are still applicable today, that I will just say, &#8220;Read the book!&#8221; It will also help to read Stuart Kauffman&#8217;s book, <a href="//anautonomousagent.com/2012/12/investigations-stuart-kauffman/" target="_blank">Investigations</a>, either before or after reading Prigogine&#8217;s book. Approaching from a different angle, Kauffman explores biological processes of nature which give rise to novelty and creative adaptive structures. Both books talk heavily about the dynamics of equilibrium and entropy. In the words of Prigogine, on page 67, &#8220;&#8230;matter at equilibrium is &#8216;blind,&#8217; but far from equilibrium it begins to &#8216;see.'&#8221; Thus, non-equilibrium systems can think and observe the world, whereas systems in equilibrium are ignorant of all outside processes.</p>
<p>The approach of Prigogine lies in understanding the importance of <a href="//www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0960077995000429" target="_blank">Poincaré Resonances</a> on dynamics and the construction/destruction of correlations at the microscopic level. How these resonances and these correlations behave leads to macroscopic features and the breaking of time symmetry. He deals with solving these Large Poincare Systems outside of the Hilbert Space; this is a concept which is important to biology and human social sciences. Because in these fields, we are always dealing with a system (human beings) which is far from equilibrium and behaves in novel and creative ways.</p>
<p>In other words, life, as  a non-equilibrium dissipative structure emerging from the non-living world, needs to be studied under the auspices of &#8220;The End of Certainty.&#8221; Irreversible processes and long range correlations are critical to understanding the development of self-organization and the novelty of life.</p>
<p>All social sciences deal with a biological organism (humans), which is a product of non-equilibrium processes. Even Prigogine and the book itself are correlated with the mass of knowledge produced by humanity in the 20th century. In other words, his ideas and those of all scientists are subject to the same non-equilibrium dynamics which Prigogine talks about in his book. Resonances and correlations in the social sphere can lead to amazing discoveries or a lack thereof.</p>
<p>One subject that I think could see development from Prigogine&#8217;s ideas is economics. Economics should be considered: &#8220;The study of non-equilibirum dissipative structures created by the self-organized social species known as <em>homo sapiens</em>, to reproduce and adapt in the biosphere called &#8216;Earth.'&#8221;</p>
<p>What I thought about the most was the concept of correlation creation and destruction. In terms of self-organizing systems and financial markets, perhaps crashes are correlation destruction events, while bubbles are correlations spreading through time. And after a crash occurs, correlations can be created which makes a crisis even worse.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/01/the-end-of-certainty-ilya-prigogine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Misbehavior of Markets: A Fractal View of Financial Turbulence &#8211; Benoit Mandelbrot</title>
		<link>/2014/08/the-misbehavior-of-markets-a-fractal-view-of-financial-turbulence-benoit-mandelbrot/</link>
		<comments>/2014/08/the-misbehavior-of-markets-a-fractal-view-of-financial-turbulence-benoit-mandelbrot/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[benoit mandelbrot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fractals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[math]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mathematics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ralph nelson elliott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robert prechter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stocks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wave theory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=26</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been wanting to read The Misbehavior of Markets: A Fractal View of Financial Turbulence by Benoit Mandelbrot for a number of years. Mandelbrot helped to change the way people view financial market dynamics. This book is definitely a must read for people working in the financial industry. However, Mandelbrot was not the first. It [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/6651341.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="//anautonomousagent.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/6651341.jpg" width="211" /></a></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">I&#8217;ve been wanting to read <a href="//amzn.com/0465043577" target="_blank">The Misbehavior of Markets: A Fractal View of Financial Turbulence</a> by <a href="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benoit_Mandelbrot" target="_blank">Benoit Mandelbrot</a> for a number of years. Mandelbrot helped to change the way people view financial market dynamics. This book is definitely a must read for people working in the financial industry. However, Mandelbrot was not the first. It is a little surprising that Mandelbrot did not talk in detail about the work of <a href="//anautonomousagent.com/?p=138" target="_blank">R.N. Elliott or Robert Prechter</a>, among others, which I think complement Mandelbrot&#8217;s work on financial fractals. Patrick Harris wrote a short paper discussing whether Mandelbrot should have cited Elliott (<a href="//www.math.utah.edu/vigre/reu/reports/harris_fall2005.pdf" target="_blank">link to paper</a>).</p>
<p>To me, the idea of infinite memory processes is one of the most important concepts touched on by Mandelbrot in this book. It suggests that economists and traders should be developing models and theories which value the importance of price series and data going back decades. And it makes sense to me that people and prices do not change their fundamental behavior over extended periods of technological evolution. However, I suspect that organisms do change their fundamental behavior if the time horizon is thousands or millions of years. I am very curious to read more about Hurst&#8217;s studies of the Nile.</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/08/the-misbehavior-of-markets-a-fractal-view-of-financial-turbulence-benoit-mandelbrot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
