<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>science &#8211; An Autonomous Agent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/science/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>exploring the noosphere</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 19:31:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Meteorite (Chondrite) and its Organisms &#8211; Otto Hahn</title>
		<link>/2019/10/the-meteorite-chondrite-and-its-organisms-otto-hahn/</link>
				<comments>/2019/10/the-meteorite-chondrite-and-its-organisms-otto-hahn/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 19:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[astrobiology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chondrite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david weinland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteorite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[otto hahn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signs of life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2608</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Petrified life-forms compose the chondrites (which represent 86% of the total number of collected meteorites to date) proposed Otto Hahn in his book, The Meteorite (Chondrite) and its Organisms, containing 142 microphotographs to serve as his proof. Published in 1880 this work took the academic community by surprise. David Weinland wrote in Das Ausland: The [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Petrified life-forms compose the chondrites (which represent 86% of the total number of collected meteorites to date) proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Otto_Hahn_(petrologist)">Otto Hahn</a> in his book, <em>The Meteorite (Chondrite) and its Organisms</em>, containing 142 microphotographs to serve as his proof. Published in 1880 this work took the academic community by surprise. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Friedrich_Weinland">David Weinland</a> wrote in <em>Das Ausland</em>:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>The result of this study is the full conviction that, at least in these  structures, we are really dealing with the remnants of corals, most of  which belong to the <em>Favositidae</em>, a family that has so far only been found as fossils in the Paleozoic, the ancient layers of Earth.</p><cite>Das Ausland, 1881, No. 16, Article 1</cite></blockquote>



<p>And also,</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Well-preserved forms are, of course, quite rare; it is mostly debris, e.g. quite similar to that observed in young ocean limestone of the Mexican Gulf. After acquiring some practice and comparing many cuts, certain recurring forms can be restored quite easily. Especially developed are the sponges of which I have already determined three specific genera.</p><cite>Das Ausland, 1881, No. 16, Article 1</cite></blockquote>



<p style="text-align:left">Reading this in <em>Das Ausland</em> must have ruffled the feathers of directors of zoology and paleontology, especially coming from Weinland, who responded to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anton_Rzehak">Anton Rzehak&#8217;s</a> <a href="https://github.com/solaranamnesis/Das-Ausland">criticism</a> with: </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>This may still seem like a venturesome statement today, but my peers, who have known me for twenty-five years, will probably know that I do not easily pronounce my conviction.</p><cite>Das Ausland, 1881, No. 26, Article 1</cite></blockquote>



<p>And indeed, Weinland went on to express his conviction by establishing <a href="https://github.com/solaranamnesis/David-Friedrich-Weinland">in a treatise</a> 16 genera each with multiple species, submitting his work to the <em>Leopoldina</em> and <em>Acta</em>, and proclaiming that:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Not ten years will pass before we will have a small universally recognized fauna of the meteorites.</p><cite>Das Ausland, 1881, No. 26, Article 1</cite></blockquote>



<p>Certainly this is a fascinating story and a book worthy of reading! And regarding Hahn&#8217;s ideas about the iron meteorites, you will want to research the ironically named <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chondrites_(genus)">Chondrites</a></em>.</p>



<p>Read: <em><a href="https://github.com/solaranamnesis/ottohahn/tree/master/DIE-METEORITE-(CHONDRITE)-UND-IHRE-ORGANISMEN">The Meteorite (Chondrite) and its Organisms</a></em></p>



<p>Read: <em><a href="https://github.com/solaranamnesis/Das-Ausland">Das Ausland</a></em><a href="https://github.com/solaranamnesis/Das-Ausland"> Articles</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2019/10/the-meteorite-chondrite-and-its-organisms-otto-hahn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microfossils and Biomolecules in Meteorites &#8211; Dr. Richard B. Hoover</title>
		<link>/2018/11/microfossils-and-biomolecules-in-meteorites-dr-richard-b-hoover/</link>
				<comments>/2018/11/microfossils-and-biomolecules-in-meteorites-dr-richard-b-hoover/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 19:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteorite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard hoover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2571</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Microfossils and Biomolecules in Meteorites &#8211; Dr. Richard B. Hoover This video by Dr. Richard B. Hoover points at why I am so interested in meteorites. Imagine if Dr. Hoover is correct and that life pervades the universe, or even lets say a large galaxy and/or group of galaxies. This is a viable outcome of [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="nCZDqOrkXb8" class="youtube" style="width: 100%; height: 360px;"></div>
<p>Microfossils and Biomolecules in Meteorites &#8211; Dr. Richard B. Hoover</p>
<p>This video by <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Richard_Hoover6">Dr. Richard B. Hoover</a> points at why I am so interested in meteorites. Imagine if Dr. Hoover is correct and that life pervades the universe, or even lets say a large galaxy and/or group of galaxies. This is a viable outcome of nature and follows from simple exponential growth given a time span on a scale of billions of years. As long as life has evolved to be able to travel the vast distances between stars this is a simple and interesting hypothesis. But we are of course mostly interested in complex life &#8212; we are scanning right now for complex information signals in all numbers of frequencies when all we have to do is study the meteorites already in our possession. If the universe is filled with single cell life forms, it would suggest that the potential of life to manifest itself in form/energy/matter such as humans or dinosaurs, etc.. exists as a latent potential throughout the region of the universe inhabited by these life forms. And complex life arises almost immediately when a new planet or moon with suitable conditions arises. This would basically be the answer to the Drake Equation. It is highly likely that there are other complex lifeforms. We now would feel confident to search for complex life signatures because we know now that the universe is filled with simple life and primitive multicelluar life like trilobites, dinosaurs, mammals, etc&#8230; So now the ultimate question would seem to be where did the first evolution of these organisms arise? In our galaxy? the Andromeda galaxy? Where exactly are Earth&#8217;s lifeforms on this larger tree of life? Reality is starting to seem like something out of a science fiction book. Of course this is just one possible speculative scenario. I can imagine others.</p>
<p>Note, I have been photographing meteorites in cross polarized light for the past few years; including CO type meteorites. You can see my work at <a href="https://solaranamnesis.com/">Solar Anamnesis</a>.</p>
<p>Also consider reading these articles:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thetricottetcollection.com/data/Mignan_Meteorite2011.pdf">Claims of Indigenous Life Forms in Meteorites: A Short Review</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.panspermia.org/chandra.htm">Chandra Wickramasinghe Testimony</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2018/11/microfossils-and-biomolecules-in-meteorites-dr-richard-b-hoover/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scale – Geoffrey West</title>
		<link>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/</link>
				<comments>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 03:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[complexity theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[didier sornette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragon-king]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geoffrey west]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa fe institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociobiology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[socionomics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2552</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Scale, by Geoffrey West, is a thought provoking book about coarse grained quantitative network theories which concern the entire human species and its interaction with the environment. Although verbose — as I think the intended audience is upper high school and entry-level college — it is clear in its depictions and explanations. This book is [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://a.co/0tTatb5">Scale</a>, by Geoffrey West, is a thought provoking book about coarse grained quantitative network theories which concern the entire human species and its interaction with the environment. Although verbose — as I think the intended audience is upper high school and entry-level college — it is clear in its depictions and explanations. This book is an important summary of really profound work and research performed at the Santa Fe Institute. And it is a great introduction to understanding power laws and scaling in biology and network topologies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2018/08/scale-geoffrey-west/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Order Out of Chaos &#8211; Ilya Prigogine and Isabelle Stengers</title>
		<link>/2018/01/order-out-of-chaos-ilya-prigogine-and-isabelle-stengers/</link>
				<comments>/2018/01/order-out-of-chaos-ilya-prigogine-and-isabelle-stengers/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 18:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[complexity theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ilya prigogine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isabelle stengers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symmetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2536</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A little bit of quantum physics, chemistry, biology and philosophy all rolled up into one important book. Order Out of Chaos (La Nouvelle Alliance as originally published in French) by Ilya Prigogine and Isabelle Stengers is a paradigm changing book. The first parts of the book are an excellent overview on the historical development of [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A little bit of quantum physics, chemistry, biology and philosophy all rolled up into one important book. <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/783285.Order_Out_of_Chaos"><em>Order Out of Chaos</em></a> (<em>La Nouvelle Alliance</em> as originally published in French) by Ilya Prigogine and Isabelle Stengers is a paradigm changing book. The first parts of the book are an excellent overview on the historical development of science &#8211; the evolution of dynamics and the discovery of thermodynamics and their relationship is particularly fascinating.</p>
<p>Once the reader gets to the later parts, it becomes somewhat abstract and the reader may not be able to get through it without a background in chemistry and physics. Chapter Nine, when the phrase &#8220;Order Out of Chaos&#8221; is developed, is difficult. Despite this, it is much more accessible than a scientific paper on the subject. It may take two or three reads to fully absorb the ideas presented. Overall it is one of my favorite reads.</p>
<p>Some important conclusions from the book:</p>
<ul>
<li>The arrow of time objectively exists and it arises from non-equilibrium and irreversibility at the microscopic level.</li>
<li>The 2nd Law of Thermodynamics can be understood as a selection principal. It operates as a negative on allowable initial conditions, in other words it restricts systems with certain initial conditions from existing.</li>
<li>Time travel to the past is not allowed by thermodynamics because time reversal requires infinite information concerning the initial conditions of the system, an impossibility to an observer in the universe. This implies that information is closely connected to irreversibility and time.</li>
<li>Thermodynamics can be expressed from dynamics through the idea of correlations and internal-time operators. Thus, dynamics has been extended once again (general relativity, quantum mechanics, and chaos theory).</li>
<li>The universe as a whole is in a non-equilibrium state and it is an irreversible process with pockets of reversible dynamics.</li>
<li>In general, one of the goals of the authors is to make dynamics and thermodynamics consistent with each other.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2018/01/order-out-of-chaos-ilya-prigogine-and-isabelle-stengers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Philosophical Overdose YouTube Channel</title>
		<link>/2017/03/philosophical-overdose-youtube-channel/</link>
				<comments>/2017/03/philosophical-overdose-youtube-channel/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 22:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1731</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Philosophical Overdose is an excellent source of material for watching/listening! Description from channel: Collection of Academic Philosophy Videos (both Analytic Philosophy &#38; Continental Philosophy): Logic, Epistemology, History of Ideas, Consciousness, Skepticism, Science, Ontology, Political Theory, Ethics, Religion, etc.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/soultorment27/videos" target="_blank">Philosophical Overdose</a> is an excellent source of material for watching/listening!</p>
<p>Description from channel:</p>
<pre>Collection of Academic Philosophy Videos (both Analytic Philosophy &amp; Continental Philosophy): Logic, Epistemology, History of Ideas, Consciousness, Skepticism, Science, Ontology, Political Theory, Ethics, Religion, etc.</pre>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2017/03/philosophical-overdose-youtube-channel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Scientist &#8211; Raphael Mechoulam</title>
		<link>/2016/11/the-scientist-raphael-mechoulam/</link>
				<comments>/2016/11/the-scientist-raphael-mechoulam/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 02:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[albert hofmann]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannabis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[documentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raphael Mechoulam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sasha shulgin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1629</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The Scientist details the life and work of Raphael Mechoulam, the grandfather of delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC). He stands in that class of wonderful thinkers which includes people like Albert Hofmann, Alexander Shulgin, among others.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Scientist details the life and work of Raphael Mechoulam, the grandfather of delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC). He stands in that class of wonderful thinkers which includes people like <a href="https://anautonomousagent.com/2016/06/the-philosophers-stone-lsd-documentary/">Albert Hofmann</a>, <a href="https://anautonomousagent.com/2016/03/dirty-pictures-2010-alexander-and-ann-shulgin-documentary/">Alexander Shulgin</a>, among others.</p>
<div class="youtube"
     id="qwfC5ye2UBk"
     style="width: 100%; height: 360px;">
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2016/11/the-scientist-raphael-mechoulam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inner Worlds, Outer Worlds (2012)</title>
		<link>/2016/05/inner-worlds-outer-worlds-2012/</link>
				<comments>/2016/05/inner-worlds-outer-worlds-2012/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 14:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cymatic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samadhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terence mckenna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1552</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Compilation of various ideas on mysticism and science.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Compilation of various ideas on mysticism and science.</p>
<p><iframe width="629" height="354" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLD8E5F0D70B62BEFE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2016/05/inner-worlds-outer-worlds-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Steps to an Ecology of Mind &#8211; Gregory Bateson</title>
		<link>/2016/03/steps-to-an-ecology-of-mind-gregory-bateson/</link>
				<comments>/2016/03/steps-to-an-ecology-of-mind-gregory-bateson/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 17:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybernetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gregory bateson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nora bateson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-reference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1485</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The papers, essays, and lectures contained in Steps to an Ecology of Mind showcase Gregory Bateson&#8217;s incredibly unique perspective. Due to the wide range of discussion within this collection, it is very difficult to write a concise summary. There are a few points which made a lasting impact in my mind. He explains the levels [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The papers, essays, and lectures contained in <a href="http://amzn.com/0226039056" target="_blank">Steps to an Ecology of Mind</a> showcase Gregory Bateson&#8217;s incredibly unique perspective. Due to the wide range of discussion within this collection, it is very difficult to write a concise summary. There are a few points which made a lasting impact in my mind.</p>
<p>He explains the levels of learning and how the animal mind can &#8220;learn about learning&#8221; and &#8220;think about thinking&#8221;; concerning humans &#8211; they can reach a third and possibly fourth level in this learning recursion hierarchy. He discusses this in the context of various subjects: anthropology, psychology, evolution, information, ecology, cybernetics and epistomoglogy in general.</p>
<p>He emphasizes that western science should adjust the way it thinks about <em>relationship and form</em> and discusses how these are relavant to the study of <em>matter and energy</em>. He questions the western conception of mammalian emotions, aesthetics, and the ego-self. On several occasions I found myself with the desire to re-read <a href="https://anautonomousagent.com/2012/12/godel-escher-bach-douglas-hofstadter/" target="_blank">Godel, Escher, Bach by Douglas Hofstadter</a>. Both books I think contain some overlap in their treatment of information and the mind. Overall, Bateson was an incredible thinker and you will improve your intellect by reading this collection of work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/steps-to-an-ecology-of-mind-gregory-bateson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Holographic Universe &#8211; Michael Talbot</title>
		<link>/2016/01/the-holographic-universe-michael-talbot/</link>
				<comments>/2016/01/the-holographic-universe-michael-talbot/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 23:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david bohm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karl pribram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael talbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stanislav grof]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1391</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[After watching an interview with Michael Talbot on YouTube, I was eager to read his book, The Holographic Universe. Despite being published in 1991, the book contains a wide range of references and resources perfect for any reader in 2016 interested in the boundary between science and the paranormal. I recommend this book, not because [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After watching an <a href="https://youtu.be/6rgYz_BU2Ew" target="_blank">interview with Michael Talbot</a> on YouTube, I was eager to read his book, <a href="http://amzn.com/0062014102" target="_blank">The Holographic Universe</a>. Despite being published in 1991, the book contains a wide range of references and resources perfect for any reader in 2016 interested in the boundary between science and the paranormal. I recommend this book, not because it provides profound new insight, but because of the huge number of paranormal examples (if legitimate) and historical occurrences with which any reader may have a difficult time fitting into their framework of reality. Of course, it is unwise to accept anything you read as truth; however, the source material is listed and the reader can stroll down any path he/she wishes in their own personal investigation of these topics. My own path is now taking me into the work of Dr. Stanislav Grof,  Rick Strassman, etc&#8230; and topics such as LSD, DMT, NDEs and OBEs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2016/01/the-holographic-universe-michael-talbot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wholeness and the Implicate Order &#8211; David Bohm</title>
		<link>/2015/09/wholeness-and-the-implicate-order-david-bohm/</link>
				<comments>/2015/09/wholeness-and-the-implicate-order-david-bohm/#disqus_thread</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 03:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david bohm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://anautonomousagent.com/?p=1334</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The collection of papers composing the book, Wholeness and the Implicate Order by David Bohm, provides an introduction to the idea of holomovement and the implicate order of the universe. In other words, the entire known and un-known universe exists as a single inseparable flow. All parts are contained in any specified part, just as [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The collection of papers composing the book, <a href="http://amzn.com/0415289793" target="_blank">Wholeness and the Implicate Order</a> by David Bohm, provides an introduction to the idea of holomovement and the implicate order of the universe. In other words, the entire known and un-known universe exists as a single inseparable flow. All parts are contained in any specified part, just as in a hologram. And all that humans observe with their biological and technological sensory apparatus are sub-regions of explicate order which form from within this whole.</p>
<p>As a metaphor, Bohm takes the experiment introduced by John Heller, shown below, and explains that the original oval shape drops of dye can be thought of as an explicate ordering of color and structure in time and space. After the experiment proceeds, this explicate order mixes into the glycerin system. Now, imagine the implicate order as consisting of the glycerin and dye system modified via the rotation. The system contains the original explicate ordering of the drops, in other words the existence of the dye as drops of individual colors is encoded by the glycerin system.</p>
<p>BUT, up to now the metaphor has been like a &#8220;time-reversal.&#8221; The real point of Bohm is that if the system is now rotated in the opposite direction, the dye will condense out of the system as an explicate order of color and shape identical to the original. This is how he suggests that the universe, i.e. the implicate order of the holomovement forms all explicate orders, including consciousness, observed by humans.</p>
<p><iframe width="629" height="472" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UpJ-kGII074?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/wholeness-and-the-implicate-order-david-bohm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
