<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>richard hoover &#8211; An Autonomous Agent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/richard-hoover/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>exploring the noosphere</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 19:12:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Microfossils and Biomolecules in Meteorites &#8211; Dr. Richard B. Hoover</title>
		<link>/2018/11/microfossils-and-biomolecules-in-meteorites-dr-richard-b-hoover/</link>
		<comments>/2018/11/microfossils-and-biomolecules-in-meteorites-dr-richard-b-hoover/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 19:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anautonomousagent]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteorite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard hoover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2571</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microfossils and Biomolecules in Meteorites &#8211; Dr. Richard B. Hoover This video by Dr. Richard B. Hoover points at why I am so interested in meteorites. Imagine if Dr. Hoover is correct and that life pervades the universe, or even lets say a large galaxy and/or group of galaxies. This is a viable outcome of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="nCZDqOrkXb8" class="youtube" style="width: 100%; height: 360px;"></div>
<p>Microfossils and Biomolecules in Meteorites &#8211; Dr. Richard B. Hoover</p>
<p>This video by <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Richard_Hoover6">Dr. Richard B. Hoover</a> points at why I am so interested in meteorites. Imagine if Dr. Hoover is correct and that life pervades the universe, or even lets say a large galaxy and/or group of galaxies. This is a viable outcome of nature and follows from simple exponential growth given a time span on a scale of billions of years. As long as life has evolved to be able to travel the vast distances between stars this is a simple and interesting hypothesis. But we are of course mostly interested in complex life &#8212; we are scanning right now for complex information signals in all numbers of frequencies when all we have to do is study the meteorites already in our possession. If the universe is filled with single cell life forms, it would suggest that the potential of life to manifest itself in form/energy/matter such as humans or dinosaurs, etc.. exists as a latent potential throughout the region of the universe inhabited by these life forms. And complex life arises almost immediately when a new planet or moon with suitable conditions arises. This would basically be the answer to the Drake Equation. It is highly likely that there are other complex lifeforms. We now would feel confident to search for complex life signatures because we know now that the universe is filled with simple life and primitive multicelluar life like trilobites, dinosaurs, mammals, etc&#8230; So now the ultimate question would seem to be where did the first evolution of these organisms arise? In our galaxy? the Andromeda galaxy? Where exactly are Earth&#8217;s lifeforms on this larger tree of life? Reality is starting to seem like something out of a science fiction book.</p>
<p>Note, I have been photographing meteorites in cross polarized light for the past few years; including CO type meteorites. You can see my work at <a href="https://solaranamnesis.com/">Solar Anamnesis</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2018/11/microfossils-and-biomolecules-in-meteorites-dr-richard-b-hoover/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
